Guide to the Mabel Loomis Todd Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Series VIII, Financial Records, documents the financial affairs of Mabel Loomis Todd. While some materials exist for the period before 1917, the majority are dated after 1917, when David Peck Todd's mental instability grew more pronounced. For example, while there are eight folders of household bills and receipts for the years 1885 through 1917, there are twenty folders for the years 1918-1932. Similarly, Mrs. Todd's financial correspondence with banks, stock-brokers, governmental agencies, contractors, and merchants is not significant before her move to Florida. Less than thirty of her one hundred and ten correspondents wrote to her before 1917.
Mabel Todd's check stubs, however, span the years 1886 through 1932 in equal proportion. In all, there are approximately one hundred and seventy books of check stubs in this series.
Financial Records also contains the many documents dealing with Mrs. Todd's Florida house, Matsuba. This includes several folders of correspondence dealing with the sale of the house after her death. Finally, this series holds several folders of miscellaneous records which include the Todd's federal income tax returns (1913, 1916, 1918) and Mabel Todd's will.
Financial Records does not contain publishers' royalty statements. These will be found in Series V filed under the individual title.
Photographs relating to Mabel Loomis Todd are arranged in the Todd-Bingham Picture Collection (Ms. Group Number 496E).
Biographical / Historical
Mabel Loomis Todd was born in Cambridge, Massachusetts, 10 November 1856, the only child of Eben Jenks Loomis and Mary Alden (Wilder) Loomis. Her father, an astronomer, mathematician, and naturalist, worked on the American Emphemeris and Nautical Almanac in Cambridge. Her mother, a descendant of many prominent Congregational ministers including John Alden of Plymouth Colony, maintained a household proud of its lineage. From the beginning, Eben and Mary Loomis instructed their daughter in all the social graces expected of a cultured nineteenth century woman.
Mabel Loomis Todd received her education in Boston and Washington, D.C., beginning school in 1865 at the Boston South End School for Young Ladies. When her father moved to Washington, D.C., in 1869, she transferred to the Georgetown Female Seminary, where she remained until 1874. For several years thereafter, she lived in Boston and studied at the New England Conservatory of Music. In 1878 she met one of the young astronomers in her father's office, David Peck Todd, and, after a thirteen month courtship, married him on 4 March 1879. One year later, she gave birth to her only child, Millicent.
Mabel Todd's relatively peaceful life ended when her husband accepted a teaching position at Amherst College in 1881 and moved the family to the small New England town of Amherst, Massachusetts. Almost immediately the Todds were accepted by the town's social elite, including its most prominent family--the Dickinsons. It proved to be a fateful association. When the Todds first met William Austin Dickinson and his wife, Susan, Mabel and Austin were immediately attracted to one another and soon began an affair. The affair, which lasted until Austin's death in 1895, created enormous resentment within the Dickinson family, resentment which surfaced in disputes over the poetry of Austin's talented sister, Emily.
Emily Dickinson, now the most famous member of the family, lived near the Todds with her sister Lavinia. Although Mabel Todd never met the reclusive poet face-to-face, she did have an opportunity to read some of her poems during her many visits to the Dickinson house. Upon Emily's death in 1886, Lavinia Dickinson tried in vain to find an editor to publish her sister's unusual poems. In desperation she approached Mabel Loomis Todd and asked her to bring Emily's poems to public attention. Mabel Todd agreed, and with the collaboration of Thomas Wentworth Higginson, she transcribed, edited, and published two volumes of Emily Dickinson's poems (1890, 1891). They were an instant success. Mabel Todd went on to edit herself a collection of Dickinson letters (1894) and a third volume of poems (1898). Mabel Loomis Todd was one of the few who recognized the skill and power of Emily Dickinson's poetry, and modern scholarship now credits her with bringing this poetry to the world.
In 1898, however, Mabel Todd stopped work on the poems due to serious conflicts with other members of the Dickinson family. These conflicts stemmed from her relationship with Austin Dickinson. After Austin's death, his widow openly opposed Mabel Todd's control of Emily Dickinson's poems, and she especially opposed her efforts to secure a piece of Dickinson land as compensation for her editorial work. Mabel Todd persuaded Lavinia Dickinson to sign over the land, but Lavinia, perhaps under pressure from Austin's widow, later claimed she had been duped. The courts agreed. This decision, along with the fact that Emily Dickinson's copyrights belonged to the Dickinson family, kept Mabel Todd from publishing any Dickinson material until 1932, when she published another volume of Dickinson letters.
Though chiefly remembered today for her work on Emily Dickinson, Mabel Todd was known by her contemporaries for her involvement in a great many other activities. Particularly active in civic affairs, she founded the Amherst Historical Society, headed the local chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution, served as the head of the Massachusetts State Federation of Women's Clubs, taught music and painting, and gave numerous recitals.
Mabel Todd also accompanied her husband on astronomical expeditions to Japan (1887, 1896), Tripoli (1900, 1905), the Dutch East Indies (1901), Chile (1907), and Russia (1914). Drawing on her experiences in these exotic foreign lands as well as her knowledge of Emily Dickinson, New England history, and astronomy, she prepared a series of popular lectures. Beginning in the early 1890s Mabel Loomis Todd went on the professional lecture circuit, traveling throughout the country. By all accounts, she was an entertaining speaker.
In addition to these activities, Mabel Todd was a prolific writer. Between 1880 and 1913 she wrote or edited twelve books and hundreds of articles on literature, astronomy, and travel.
In 1913, Mabel Todd suffered a cerebral hemorrhage which left her disabled for several months. Although she remained active in civic affairs after her recovery, her writing and speaking activities declined precipitously. David Peck Todd's erratic behavior at this time created still more problems. When her husband's increasing mental instability finally forced him into early retirement, the family left Amherst and moved to Miami, Florida. In 1922 David Todd's disorders became so severe that he was institutionalized. Mabel Todd, however, continued to lead an active social life in Florida, involving herself in many civic causes. She also devoted a large portion of her time to the preservation of nature and the wilderness.
Mabel Loomis Todd died 14 October 1932, the victim of a second cerebral hemorrhage.
Adultery; Architecture, Domestic -- Designs and plans; Art, Japanese -- Meiji period, 1868-1912; Astronomy; Child care; Childbirth; Courtship; Drawing -- 19th century; Education -- United States; Families; Literature -- History and criticism; Marriage; Middle class; Solar eclipses; Upper class; Women artists; Women authors; Women -- Education; Women -- Employment; Women -- Social conditions; Women -- Societies and clubs; Wood-engraving -- 19th century -- Japan; Amherst (Mass.) -- Social life and customs; Europe; Florida -- Social life and customs; New England -- History; Soviet Union; United States -- Description and travel; United States -- Social life and customs; Washington (D.C.) -- Social life and customs; Autobiographies; Autographs; Diaries; Scrapbooks; Speeches; Authors; Editors; Abbott, Lyman, 1835-1922; Adams, Mary C.; Alcott, Louisa May, 1832-1888; Allen, Hervey, 1889-1949; Andrews, Caro Lovejoy; Bianchi, Martha Dickinson, 1866-1943; Bingham, Millicent Todd, 1880-1968; Brown, Katherine M. Brooks; Cable, George Washington, 1844-1925; Chase, Ada H.; Compton, Naomi; Dakin, Arthur Hazard, 1905-; Deering, James; Dewey, Melvil, 1851-1931; Dickinson, Edward, 1803-1874; Dickinson, Emily, 1830-1886; Dickinson, Lavinia Norcross, 1833-1899; Dickinson, Austin, 1829-1895; Fowler, Georgiana; Gorgas, William Crawford, 1854-1920; Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1823-1911; Hilder, Howard, 1866-1935; Howe, Julia Ward, 1819-1910; Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920; Hubbard, Elbert Hamilton, 1849-1912; James, Arthur Curtiss, 1867-1941; James, Harriett Parsons; Jeans, James, 1877-1946; Keep, Austin Baxter, 1875-1932; Keep, Wallace; Kittredge, Karrie; Leighton, Cora Rutherford; Loomis, Eben Jenks, 1828-1912; Loomis, Harriet Elwell Bagg; Loomis, Mary Alden Wilder, 1831-1910; Lovell, Percival, 1855-1916; Lowell, Amy, 1874-1925; Meiklejohn, Alexander, 1872-1964; Mitchell, Annie Olivia Tiffany, 1844-1937; Munroe, Mabel Stearns; Newcomb, Simon, 1835-1909; Palmer, Alice Freeman, 1855-1902; Palmer, George Herbert, 1842-1933; Pickering, Edward C. (Edward Charles), 1846-1919; Rhode, Ruth Bryan Owen, 1855-1944; Rusch, Henry A.; Saint-Gaudens, Augusta; Schiff, Jacob H. (Jacob Henry), 1847-1920; Smith, Henry Preserved, 1847-1927; Stearns, Alfred E. (Alfred Ernest), 1871-1949; Stearns, Arthur French, 1864-; Stearns, Mary E. Kittredge; Thoreau, Maria, 1794-1881; Todd, David P. (David Peck), 1855-1939; Todd, Mabel Loomis, 1856-1932; Twiss, Stephen Prince, 1827-; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977; Walker, Francis Amasa, 1840-1897; Ward, Lydia Avery Coonley, 1845-1924; Whitin, Sarah E.; Wiggin, Kate Douglas Smith, 1856-1923; Wilder, John Augustus, 1834-1912; Loomis family; Wilder family; Amherst College; Boston Authors Club; Amherst Historical Society (Amherst, Mass.)
- Juvenilia, 1863-1879; Series I; 1.75 linear feet (5 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  JUVENILIA has four sections: Correspondence, Education, Writings, and Memorabilia.
  Correspondence is divided into General and Family Correspondence. Letters are arranged alphabetically by author. Letters from two or more members of the same family or two or more offices of the same institution have sometimes been interfiled together in a single folder. In such cases the individuals or offices are all listed separately; the inclusive date of material in the folder appears next to the first name only. Letters written by Mabel Todd are filed under the name of the recipient.
  Education has three divisions: Compositions, Notebooks, and Reports, Catalogues, Fees. Each division is arranged chronologically.
  Writings contains both published and unpublished materials arranged chronologically within each division.
  Memorabilia is arranged by type of material (i.e. invitations, programs, etc.).
  - General Correspondence
    - A-C, 1872-1879 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alcott, Louisa May, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Allen, Susan, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brown, Bettine B., 1874, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Chase, Mrs. Ada, 1876-1879 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cutter, H. Maria, 1867-1879 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - D-H, 1869-1879 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dyer, Isaac Watson, 1874, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ellison, S. T., 1868, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Garland, Johannes, 1876, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Goodrich, Charles N., 1870-1878 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Goodrich, Sarah L. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Hoar, Mary, 1877-1879 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hooper, E. G., 1875-1879 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Hoover, Clara, 1872-1876, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Hubbard, Sadie Lizzie, 1868, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - J-L, 1871-1878 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Lenmon, Isobel, 1876-1878 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Lincoln, Walter, 1871-1873 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Lipscomb, S. A., 1873, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - M-P, 1872-1878 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Newcomb, Simon, Mrs. Newcomb and family, 1878, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Nourse, Emma S., 1874 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Otis, Agnes Pauline, 1877-1879, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Otis, Anna Maria (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Paige, Dell F., 1869, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Pickerell, Clara, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Reading, Lillie C., 1872,1873 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - S-W; unidentified, 1866-1879 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Sewall, Lizzie C., 1874, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Shaw, Susie H., 1876-1879 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Shoemaker, Edith L., 1871-1875 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Shoemaker, W. L. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Steele, Lotta M., 1876 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Tenney, Ann J., 1869-1872 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Tenney, Ann M. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Tenney, Julia Moore (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Thoreau, Maria, 1877-1879 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Thoreau, Sophia E., 1875 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Valentine, Lottie G., 1875-1879 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Vinton, Marie A., 1877, 1878, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Ward, Eva, 1868-1872 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Wills, Frank J., 1874-1878 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Winchell, J. P., 1875 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Selected letters from gentlemen, 1874-1878, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Selected letters: Abbott, Ezra Lincoln, 1875, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Selected letters: Brown, Harry B., 1872-1874 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Family Correspondence
    - Bagg, Harriet Elwall, 1868-1879 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Compton, Naomi, 1878, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Jones, Maria B., 1867-1872 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Loomis, Eben J., 1863-1878 October (Box 2, Folder 46-60)
    - Loomis, Kate Ashley (Kitty), 1869, 1870 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Loomis, "Aunt Libbie", 1879 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Loomis, Mary A., 1863-1878 October (Box 2, Folder 63-69)
    - Loomis, Nathan, 1861, 1863 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Mason, Clara, 1876-1879 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Mason, Nellie E. (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Mason, William A., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Stearns, George Harmon, [1876?] (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Stevens, Susan, [1871?] (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Todd, David Peck, 1878 February-1879 January (Box 2, Folder 74-79)
    - Wilder, E. F., 1879 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Wilder, John Augustus, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Wilder, Mary W. F. Jones, 1865-1879 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Education
    - Reports, catalogues and fees, 1865-1875 (Box 3, Folder 83-84)
    - Compositions, 1868-1875, undated (Box 3, Folder 85-90)
    - Notebooks, 1870-1873, undated (Box 3, Folder 91-93)
  - Writings
    - Diaries, 1866-1875 (Box 3, Folder 94-97)
    - Journal, 1867 November (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Unpublished writings, 1867-1872 (Box 3, Folder 99-100)
    - Unpublished writings, 1873-1877, undated (Box 4, Folder 101-112)
    - Published articles
      - "My Summer at Lake Champlain", Our Young Folk, 1871 August (Box 4, Folder 113)
      - "The Japanese", Our Young Folk, 1872 June (Box 4, Folder 114)
      - "Letter from Maine", Forney's Sunday Chronicle, 1874 (Box 4, Folder 115)
      - "Washington Jottings", Youth's Companion, 1874-1875 (Box 4, Folder 116)
      - "A Quite Nook in Maine", Boston Transcript, 1875 July 8 (Box 4, Folder 117)
      - "Maine Fogs", Boston Transcript, 1875 August 20 (Box 4, Folder 118)
      - "Hampton Legends", Boston Transcript Memorabilia, 1876 July 29 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Memorabilia
    - Programs, 1869-1879 (Box 4, Folder 120-124)
    - Greeting cards, Undated (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Georgetown Female Seminary, 1878-1899 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Newspaper references to Mabel Loomis, 1874, 1879, undated (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Autograph book, 1869-1870 (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - Hair book, Undated (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - "Herbarium", 1868 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Drawings, memorabilia, painted rocks, 1867 (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - Miscellaneous printed matter, 1871-1879, undated (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1862-1877, undated (Box 5, Folder 132)
- Correspondence, 1879-1932; Series II; 14 linear feet (33 boxes)
  CORRESPONDENCE has two sections: General and Family. Letters are arranged alphabetically by author. Letters from two or more members of the same family or two or more offices of the same institution have sometimes been interfiled together in a single folder. In such cases the individuals or offices are all listed separately; the inclusive date of material in the folder appears next to the first name only. Letters written by Mabel Todd are filed under the name of the recipient.
  - General Correspondence
    - Notebooks with lists of letters, 1893 February-1915 March (Box 6, Folder 1-10)
    - Unbound lists of letters, 1919-1932 (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
    - Aa-Am, 1896-1932, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Abbott, A.F.H., 1899, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Abbott, Herbert V. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Abbott, Lyman (Box 6, Folder 14)
      General
      See also: box 19, folder 532.
    - Adams, Joseph H., 1928, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Adams, Mary C. (Mrs. Charles D.), 1898, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Adams, O.F., 1890-1907 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Adams, W.F., 1908-1915 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Adriance, Vanderpoel, 1896-1905 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Allen, Charles H., 1900 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Allen, Francis P., 1910, 1911 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Allen, H.N. and Frances M., 1908-1918 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Allen, Harriet C., 1898-1903, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Allen, Helen M., 1905, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Allen, Hervey, 1923, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Allien, Mabel Carrington King (Mrs. Victor S.), 1929-1932 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Ambrose, N.L. (Mrs. J.H.), 1924, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - The American Book Company, 1899-1900, 1905, 1911, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Ames, Katherine H., 1908-1912 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Amherst College, 1906-1924 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Amherst Graduates Quarterly (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Ammidon, Nellie A, 1883, 1889 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Ammidon, Philip (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - An-Az, 1881-1930 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Anderson, Ella Denny, Undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Anderson, Harriet, 1911-1913 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Anderson, Katherine H., 1893-1999 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Andrews, Caro Lovejoy (Mrs. John), 1884-1908 (Box 7, Folder 36-38)
    - Andrews, John A., 1885 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Anthony, Clara R., 1907-1920, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Anthony, Sarah Cox, 1905-1912, undated (Box 7, Folder 41-45)
    - Armstrong, Dullie M., 1928-1932 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Armstrong, Louise H., 1892-1898 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Arnold, Tirzah S. (Mrs. George F.), 1918-1920 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Atkinson, Edith M., 1925-1932 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Avery, A. S., 1926, 1927, undated (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Baa-Bad, 1896-1931, undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Bai-Bak, 1891-1924 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Bal-Bar, 1885-1931, undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Bas-Bau, 1885, 1900-1924, undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Bacon, Alice M., 1904 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Bailey, Alice Ward, 1898-1913, undated (Box 7, Folder 56-58)
    - Baker, Ella Jessup, 1899-1908 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Baker, Elnora Wanda (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Baker, Robert H., 1907, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Banks, Edgar J., 1924-1931 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Barron, C.W., 1927 (Box 7, Folder 62)
      See also: box 92, folder 3.
    - Barrons, Cecelia A., 1910-1932 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Bartlett, Arthur K., 1901, 1902 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Bates, William A., 1921, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Baxter, Arthur K., 1912-1916, undated (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Bayley, Katherine, 1898-1911 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Be, 1885-1930 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Belmore, Bruce, 1928, undated (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Benedict, E. C., 1917, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Bi, 1887-1925 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Bigelow, Mary S., 1889, 1890 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Bigler, Katherine Soden (Mrs. Albert), 1927-1928 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Bikle, Lucy L.C. (Mrs. Henry Wolf), 1926 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Bill, Nathan D., 1898, 1906 (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Bill, Ruth W. (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Billings, Lillie Brinerhoff (Mrs. Dwight M.), 1909-1915 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Bird, Anna C., 1919-1927, undated (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Bird, Joanne (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Bishop, E. M., 1895 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Bispham, Clarence Wyatt, 1885-1903, undated (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Bispham, Laura W. (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Bispham, William (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Bl-Bo, 1889-1930 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Blackburn, Henry, 1885, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Blackburn, Kathleen (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Blodgett, Benjamin E., 1882-1929 (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Blodgett, Fanny (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Bosler, H., 1918-1931 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - Boston Herald, 1896-1897, 1905 (Box 8, Folder 84)
    - Bousch, Anna Camm, 1917-1920 (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - Boyd, K. Willard, 1926-1931 (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - Br, 1884-1924 (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Bradford, Lydia Allen DeVilbiss, Undated (Box 8, Folder 88)
      See also: box 10, folder 167.
    - Brady, Mary Seelys, 1889, undated (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Brazier, Marion H., 1897-1923 (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - Bridgeman, Amy S., 1920, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Bridgman, Herbert L. (Brooklyn Standard Union), 1908-1916 (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - Bridgman, Howard A., 1893 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Brown, Alice, 1890-1898 (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - Brown, A.N., 1927-1931 (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Brown, Annie Dickinson (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Brown, Bettina, 1879-1909 (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - Brown, Katherine M. Brooks, 1892-1907 (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Bu-By, 1890-1931 (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - Buffum, Vryling Wilder, Undated (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - Bulkley, Barry, 1890-1922 (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - Bumpus, Louise, 1896, undated (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Burnett, Carrie, 1896-1909 (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Burnett, Charles T. (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Burnham, Carrie W., 1894-1903 (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Burnham, Clara Avery (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Burnham, Edmund (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Burnham, Mary Wesley (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Burton, M.L., 1911, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Burton, Nina M. (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Caa-Cam, 1896-1920, undated (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Caa-Cas, 1889-1930, undated (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - Cable, Eva, 1907, 1918, undated (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - Cable, George W., 1894-1896, 1898, 1904-1908, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - Cable, Louise S., 1893, 1895, 1898-1901, undated (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - Cable, Lucy, 1894, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - Cable, Margaret, 1904, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - Cable, Mary, Undated (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - Carman, William W., 1921-1923 (Box 8, Folder 111)
      See also: box 90, folder 15.
    - Carpenter, Alice, 1900s, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 112)
    - Carpenter, C.C., 1899-1914 (Box 8, Folder 113)
    - Carr, Fannie Smith, 1894-1913, undated (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - Carr, Lucy W. (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - Ce-Cl, 1898-1932 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - Chadwick, James R., 1897, 1898 (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - Chant, Laura Ormiston, 1890-1902 (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - Chapin, Mary E.T., 1894-1908 (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - Chase, Ada H., 1880-1904 (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - Child, Edwin B., 1890-1930 (Box 9, Folder 120)
    - Church, Katherine Barnard, 1917, 1925, undated (Box 9, Folder 121)
    - Churchill, Annie S., 1919-1923 (Box 9, Folder 122)
    - Churchill, Bella Whittier (Box 9, Folder 122)
    - Churchill, Elbert L. (Box 9, Folder 122)
    - Churchill, George B. (Box 9, Folder 122)
    - Cl, 1898-1930 (Box 9, Folder 123)
    - Clark, Eliazer Winslow, 1923-1930 (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - Clark, Louise M.D., 1882-1887 (Box 9, Folder 125-127)
    - Clark, John Bates, 1897-1915, undated (Box 9, Folder 128)